This is Minecraft, the game that screwed its community so hard that we're about to sue them in a class action lawsuit.
这是《Minecraft》，这款游戏把它的社区坑得如此之惨，以至于我们即将对他们发起集体诉讼。
You see, in December of 2024, I uploaded this video in which I exposed Mojang
你看，在 2024 年 12 月，我上传了这段视频，在其中我揭露了 Mojang
the creators of Minecraft, for breaking consumer protection law and exposing children to gambling.
也就是《Minecraft》的开发者，违反了消费者保护法，并让儿童接触到赌博。
And while I tried to seek justice for myself
而当我试图为自己寻求公正时
I wasn't able to do so because my government is kind of incompetent
我没能做到，因为我的政府有点无能
making access to justice basically impossible if you're not rich as fuck.
如果你不是特别有钱，基本上就不可能获得公正。
So I tried adding a GoFundMe campaign at the end to finance a class action lawsuit
所以我尝试在最后加上一个 GoFundMe 筹款活动，用来资助一场集体诉讼
because this wasn't something that affected just me.
因为这并不是只影响到我一个人的事情。
And obviously, there's no way that would actually work
而且显然，这根本不可能真的奏效
right?
对吧？
YouTuber Kiabru- Is suing Mojang.
YouTuber Kiabru——正在起诉 Mojang。
Illegally changing- They publicly funded- It's already nearly on a million Gs.
非法更改——他们是公开筹资的——已经接近一百万美元了。
19 on trending right now.
目前在趋势榜上排名第 19。
It's exceeded it.
它已经超越了。
Completed its funding.
已完成融资。
Already passed- $120,000.
已经超过——12 万美元。
That's a lot.
真多啊。
No way the class- Dude, look at this.
不可能是班级——哥们，看看这个。
That's gotta be one of the fastest-growing crowdfunding campaigns.
这一定是增长最快的众筹活动之一。
We raised $150,000 within days.
我们在几天内就筹集了 15 万美元。
Oh, it's fucking happening.
哦，这他妈的真的要成了。
Where we now have access to legal representation and can proceed with the class action lawsuit.
我们现在可以获得法律代理，并可以继续进行集体诉讼。
Yes.
是的。
My name is Bjorn Persson.
我叫 Bjorn Persson。
I'm a member of the Swedish Borrower Association.
我是瑞典借款人协会的成员。
I run a law firm together with my colleague
我和我的同事一起经营一家律师事务所
Conny Larsson.
Conny Larsson。
And we're working with this lawsuit since it's part of our practice and are looking to
我们正在处理这起诉讼，因为它是我们业务的一部分，并且我们希望
um, run this, uh, lawsuit as a class action against Mojang because we think it's an important issue that needs to be addressed.
嗯，将这起诉讼作为针对 Mojang 的集体诉讼来进行，因为我们认为这是一个需要解决的重要问题。
To give you a little recap, Minecraft is one of those games that anyone can modify to add things that it didn't originally have.
简单回顾一下，Minecraft 是那种任何人都可以修改、添加原本没有的内容的游戏之一。
And what I wanted to do was add guns to the game to recreate an old game that I used to play as a child that had unfortunately been shut down.
我想做的是在游戏中加入枪支，以重现我小时候玩过的一款老游戏，但那款游戏不幸已经停运了。
But right as it was about to release
但就在它即将发布的时候
Mojang said that, "A recent directive from Mojang leadership determined that guns and weapons were considered non-compliant features.
Mojang 表示：“Mojang 高层最近的指令认定，枪支和武器被视为不合规的功能。”
" Meaning that they had to be completely removed
这意味着它们必须被彻底移除
implying the shutdown of dozens of projects, including mine.
这暗示着包括我的项目在内的数十个项目被关闭。
But when actually looking into it, even though they said that guns and weapons were specifically prohibited by the game's legal agreement
但当真正去调查时，尽管他们说游戏的法律协议中明确禁止枪支和武器
when actually looking for these specific prohibitions, you'd come to find that they didn't actually exist.
当你真正去寻找这些具体的禁令时，你会发现它们实际上并不存在。
So Mojang was making shit up and pretending it was part of the Terms of Service
所以 Mojang 只是在胡编乱造，并假装这些是服务条款的一部分
a type of contract, which as you've guessed
一种合同类型，正如你所猜到的
is kind of illegal.
有点违法。
A contract is an agreement between two parties and both parties need to agree what the meaning of the contract is.
合同是双方之间的协议，双方都需要就合同的含义达成一致。
You can't be forced into new rules that apply to your contract unless you've been notified
除非你已被告知，否则不能被强制适用合同中的新规则。
as well as having a choice whether to actually accept those terms or just be able to keep using what you already have.
以及可以选择是否真正接受这些条款，或者只是继续使用你已经拥有的东西。
And since this is a hidden clause where guns are just one of the many examples that exist
而且由于这是一个隐藏条款，枪支只是其中众多例子之一
Mojang can do whatever they want, like applying a different version of the same clause so you never know which one you're gonna get
Mojang 可以随心所欲，比如应用同一条款的不同版本，这样你永远不知道自己会遇到哪一个版本
changing their minds at any time, like they did with the guns three times
随时改变主意，就像他们在枪支问题上那样，已经改了三次。
and even go against their own rules, like allowing gambling even though they publicly pretend like it's forbidden.
甚至会违背自己的规则，比如明明公开假装禁止赌博，却依然允许赌博。
But obviously, shit gets worse.
但显然，情况会变得更糟。
Because when a company changes its terms of service
因为当一家公司更改其服务条款时
it's required to notify its users about the changes and get their agreement for it.
它必须通知用户这些更改，并获得用户的同意。
And out of the 47 times they changed their legal agreements
而在他们 47 次更改法律协议的过程中
they never told anyone about it.
他们从未向任何人提起过这件事。
We know this because I went through thousands of archived pages for every single legal agreement that the game has ever had to see if a single word had changed.
我们之所以知道这一点，是因为我翻阅了该游戏有史以来的每一份法律协议的数千个存档页面，只为查看是否有哪怕一个字发生了变化。
And Mojang not notifying anyone of changes makes perfect sense
而 Mojang 不通知任何人这些更改是完全说得通的。
since in their own words, "It is up to you to check back to see if these guidelines have changed
因为用他们自己的话来说，“是否查看这些指南是否已更改取决于你自己
" so that it's not their responsibility to tell you.
”，所以这不是他们有责任告诉你的事情。
There's a lot of things that you really can't do with the contract and have it enforceable against the consumers.
合同中有很多事情你实际上不能做，否则它将无法对消费者产生法律效力。
You have this legislation under European consumer law that
根据欧洲消费者法，你有这样的立法
uh, mandates that the company that changes
呃，规定更改条款的公司
uh, the terms need to inform the consumers about this.
呃，需要将此事告知消费者。
And they can't enforce the, the new changes without giving
而且他们不能在不给
uh, the consumers a choice.
呃，消费者选择的情况下执行这些新变更。
And if not telling anyone wasn't already bad enough- They removed the notice when the software terms were updated.
如果不告知任何人已经不够糟糕的话——他们在软件条款更新时还移除了通知。
This is obviously making it harder for the consumers to exercise their rights.
这显然让消费者更难行使他们的权利。
Because not only is it our responsibility to check when changes happen
因为不仅我们有责任去检查何时发生了变化
but they also make it borderline impossible to tell when they actually did.
而且他们还让我们几乎不可能分辨出这些变化究竟是什么时候发生的。
Which is quite ironic coming from the company that says
这话出自那家公司，真是颇具讽刺意味
"We are trying to be open, honest
“我们努力做到开放、诚实
and most importantly, trusting.
而且最重要的是，值得信任。”
" But of course, it only gets worse.
但当然，情况只会变得更糟。
Remember how the original email from Mojang said that guns were specifically prohibited by these three legal agreements where one of them didn't even exist?
还记得 Mojang 的原始邮件是怎么说的吗？他们声称枪支在这三份法律协议中被明确禁止，而其中一份协议甚至根本不存在？
This is something I even pointed out in the last video.
这一点我在上一个视频中就已经指出过了。
By the Mojang brand guidelines, guidelines that literally do not exist.
根据 Mojang 的品牌指南——实际上并不存在的指南。
Well, it turns out that they do exist as its own hidden internal document under a strict NDA that does contain the prohibitions for guns.
结果发现，它们确实存在于一份严格保密协议下的内部隐藏文件中，其中确实包含了对枪械的禁止规定。
The very same document where Mojang internally recognizes loot boxes as gambling.
正是在同一份文件中，Mojang 在内部将战利品箱认定为赌博。
And what pisses me off even more than them trying to apply a contract that was literally impossible to access without whistleblowers was that while they left us on hold for six months because their CEO was on vacation
比起他们试图执行一份如果没有举报人根本无法获取的合同，更让我恼火的是，他们因为 CEO 在度假而让我们被搁置了六个月
they officially partnered with Nerf, the gun company
却正式与玩具枪公司 Nerf 建立了合作关系
even though these guidelines say that gun-like toys are forbidden.
尽管这些指南明确规定禁止类似枪支的玩具。
Fucking hypocrites.
该死的伪君子。
But as you probably guessed it, it only gets worse.
但正如你可能已经猜到的，情况只会变得更糟。
You see, when buying Minecraft, you create a Mojang account that is then used to play the game.
你看，当你购买《Minecraft》时，你会创建一个 Mojang 账号，然后用它来玩游戏。
At least, that's how it used to be.
至少，过去一直是这样的。
Because Mojang was bought by Microsoft in 2014
因为 Mojang 在 2014 年被微软收购
where just a few years later, Mojang would announce that
而仅仅几年后，Mojang 就会宣布
"We've decided that moving forward, all of our games will require a Microsoft account to play.
我们已决定，从现在开始，我们所有的游戏都将需要使用 Microsoft 账户才能游玩。
And if you didn't want to migrate your account
如果你不想迁移你的账户
you won't be able to log in anymore
你将无法再登录
which means you won't be able to play either.
这意味着你也将无法玩游戏。
" In other words, either migrate your account and give Microsoft all of your data
换句话说，要么迁移你的账户并将你的所有数据交给 Microsoft
or they take away what you paid for.
要么他们就会收回你付费购买的东西。
And this is what you call a threat.
而这就是你所谓的威胁。
But not only did they threaten everyone, they also sneakily modified their terms of service to give themselves permission to cancel your account if they simply felt like it.
但他们不仅威胁了所有人，还偷偷修改了服务条款，让自己有权在心血来潮时取消你的账户。
And you see, when purchasing a game like Minecraft
你看，当你购买像 Minecraft 这样的游戏时
that essentially means that you purchased a license to download and play the game where the conditions of that license are within the terms of service.
这基本上意味着你购买了一个许可，可以在遵守服务条款的条件下下载并游玩该游戏。
This is important because if a company wanted to change the way a service works
这很重要，因为如果一家公司想要改变某项服务的运作方式
by, for example, changing their terms of service
例如，通过更改他们的服务条款
that new version would only apply to the new users or the ones that explicitly agreed to the changes.
该新版本只适用于新用户或那些明确同意更改的用户。
In simple terms, if the contract used to say that you will be able to play the game
简单来说，如果合同中原本写明你将能够玩这款游戏
if the company doesn't like that anymore, they can't take it away from you because that would be called breach of contract
如果公司后来不再愿意这样做，他们不能剥夺你的权利，因为那将被视为违约。
which is kind of illegal.
这有点违法。
And what happened here was that Mojang was forcing everyone to migrate
这里发生的事情是 Mojang 强制所有人进行迁移
saying things like, "You will not be able to access the game.
说着类似“你将无法访问游戏”这样的话。
Migration is mandatory.
迁移是强制性的。
Won't be able to play Minecraft.
将无法玩《Minecraft》。
Must be migrated to a Microsoft.
必须迁移到 Microsoft。
" Players need to move to a Microsoft account.
“玩家需要迁移到 Microsoft 账户。
Mojang accounts to Microsoft accounts.
将 Mojang 账户迁移到 Microsoft 账户。
Where funnily enough, they had the balls to say that this was voluntary three times.
有趣的是，他们竟然有胆量三次说这是自愿的。
So voluntary, in fact, that if you didn't do it
事实上是如此“自愿”，以至于如果你不这样做
they took away what you paid for.
他们夺走了你所付费的东西。
This was a forced migration, where we obviously didn't have much of a choice.
这是一次被迫的迁移，我们显然没有太多选择。
The only choice you had was to terminate your account.
你唯一的选择就是注销你的账户。
And not only were they forcing everyone to give-.
而且他们不仅强迫所有人交出——
..
……
their data to a company with a world record of privacy violations
他们的数据给一家拥有隐私侵犯世界纪录的公司
which got recently fined $20 million by the FTC for illegally collecting information on children
最近因非法收集儿童信息而被 FTC 罚款 2000 万美元
most Minecraft players are children.
大多数《Minecraft》玩家都是儿童。
But in doing so, they also forced you to agree to Microsoft and Xbox's legal agreements
但在这样做的过程中，他们也迫使你同意了 Microsoft 和 Xbox 的法律协议
all under the threat of them taking away what you paid for if you didn't do what they wanted.
如果你不按他们的要求去做，就会面临他们夺走你已付费物品的威胁。
A contract needs to, uh, be entered into freely
合同需要，呃，自愿签订
and that obviously means that you need to have a
而这显然意味着你需要拥有一个
a choice between agreeing or not agreeing.
在同意或不同意之间做出选择。
Just presenting one choice is not really, uh
只提供一个选择其实并不算，呃
an agreement.
一种协议。
But even though it was illegal, Mojang still went ahead with it
但即使这是非法的，Mojang 仍然继续推进
which resulted in millions of people losing access to what they paid for
这导致数百万人失去了他们所付费购买的内容的使用权
some of which were never even notified that it was happening to begin with
其中有些人甚至从一开始就没有收到任何通知
only finding out years later that their purchase had been nullified.
多年后才发现他们的购买已被作废。
But when actually contacting Mojang to complain, you'd come to find that they wouldn't answer questions
但当真正联系 Mojang 投诉时，你会发现他们不会回答问题
and automatically close most tickets asking for answers.
并会自动关闭大多数要求答复的工单。
And when asking Microsoft about it, they would say that.
当询问微软时，他们会这么说。
..
"I've discussed your issue with Mojang support and came to the conclusion that the migration is within the Minecraft Terms and Conditions.
“我已与 Mojang 支持团队讨论了你的问题，并得出结论，迁移符合《Minecraft 条款与条件》。
" In other words, "We've investigated ourselves and found nothing wrong.
换句话说，“我们自查后发现自己没有任何问题。”
" But unfortunately for them, this user knows his rights.
“但不幸的是，对他们来说，这位用户知道自己的权利。”
And when asking Microsoft to cite his contract for where it says that a Microsoft account is required to play
当要求微软引用合同中说明必须拥有 Microsoft 账户才能游玩的条款时
Microsoft said, "End User License Agreements are constantly updated.
微软表示：“最终用户许可协议会不断更新。
Please refer to the current one," where the current one says
请参阅当前版本”，而当前版本中写道
"If you originally signed up through a Mojang account
“如果您最初是通过 Mojang 账户注册的
you must migrate to a Microsoft account in order to keep using the services.
你必须迁移到 Microsoft 账户才能继续使用这些服务。
" But this wasn't part of the contract when the user had bought the game
“但这在用户购买游戏时并不是合同的一部分
to which Microsoft replied, "I understand that this is your interpretation
对此 Microsoft 回应道：“我理解这是你的理解
but this EULA applies for any user regardless of the date of creation
但本最终用户许可协议适用于任何用户，无论创建日期如何
" further stating that, "Your contract is the new EULA.
并进一步声明：“您的合同是新的最终用户许可协议。
The old one doesn't apply anymore.
旧的已不再适用。
You agreed to these Terms by using the service.
您在使用本服务时即表示同意这些条款。
" Where they then immediately closed the ticket
“然后他们立即关闭了工单
refusing to answer any further questions.
拒绝回答任何进一步的问题。
And this is a perfect example of fucking up in writing
而这正是写作中搞砸的一个完美例子
because it confirms the idea that.
因为它印证了这样的想法。
..
It is up to you to check back to see if these guidelines have changed.
是否有这些指南的变更，需要你自己回来查看。
And that they don't care about agreement, since they claim that you agreed to changes that they didn't even tell you about.
而且他们并不在乎是否达成一致，因为他们声称你已经同意了他们甚至没有告知你的更改。
So Mojang voided everyone's contract since they say that they don't apply anymore.
所以 Mojang 宣布所有人的合同作废，因为他们说这些合同已经不再适用。
And you fucking guessed it, this is breach of contract.
没错，你他妈的猜对了，这就是违约。
And if that wasn't bad enough, when actually looking at the historical changes to the contracts
如果这还不够糟糕的话，当你真正去查看合同的历史变更时
there used to be a clause that says that you will be able to play the game even if you don't agree to the new changes
以前还有一条条款写着，即使你不同意新的变更，你也能继续玩游戏。
all of which were, of course, sneakily removed during the migration.
当然，这些在迁移过程中都被偷偷移除了。
I would say that this, uh, forceful way of
我会说，这种，呃，强制性的
um, migrating the customers is not a term that is enforceable by Microsoft
嗯，将客户迁移的方式，并不是微软可以强制执行的条款。
which in this case would mean that they would be forced to reinstate the old accounts.
在这种情况下，这将意味着他们将被迫恢复旧账户。
And all of this is essentially what the class action lawsuit is about.
而这一切本质上正是集体诉讼的核心内容。
Minecraft's success is entirely due to the community making it what it is
Minecraft 的成功完全归功于社区将它塑造成如今的样子。
through, for example, mods and servers, because the base game in itself isn't really that interesting.
例如，通过模组和服务器，因为基础游戏本身并不是那么有趣。
And when the very things that we depend on to actually enjoy the game are being threatened by a company that ignores our rights like this
而当我们真正依赖来享受游戏的那些东西，被一家这样无视我们权利的公司威胁时
we as consumers end up being affected because Mojang is restricting the way we're able to play the game.
作为消费者的我们最终会受到影响，因为 Mojang 正在限制我们玩游戏的方式。
On top of them literally taking the game away under threat simply because they knew that nobody would be fighting back.
他们之所以在威胁下直接把游戏拿走，只是因为他们知道没人会反抗。
But there's a limit to the amount of shit that people are willing to take before taking measures.
但人们能忍受的烂事是有限的，超过这个限度就会采取行动。
And Mojang?
至于 Mojang 呢？
You fucking crossed it, because we're not begging or asking for mercy anymore.
你他妈的越界了，因为我们不再乞求或请求怜悯了。
This is a class action lawsuit that you cannot ignore.
这是一起你无法忽视的集体诉讼。
I think this is an important, uh
我认为这是一个重要的，呃
case for this reason that this is becoming a general business practice right now
正因如此，这正在成为一种普遍的商业做法
and it's not supposed to be like that when you're dealing with consumers
而在与消费者打交道时，本不应该是这样的
especially children.
尤其是对待儿童时。
We are seeing a lot of companies coming out with this claim that you don't get the full terms of service or for their product when you buy it.
我们看到很多公司声称，当你购买他们的产品时，你并不能获得完整的服务条款。
The company you're buying from refer you to their
你购买的公司会将你引导至他们
uh, contractual terms on the website, which can change at any time
呃，网站上的合同条款，而这些条款可能随时更改。
basically depriving you all your consumer rights.
基本上剥夺了你所有的消费者权益。
And this is not right.
而这是不对的。
This is something really needed to, uh
这确实是需要，呃
act upon and make sure that we can exer- exercise our consumer rights.
采取行动并确保我们能够行使消费者权利。
And our objectives are quite simple.
我们的目标非常简单。
Revert the account migration, meaning the reinstatement of all unmigrated accounts where Mojang in the EU has to be the owner of all customer data
撤销账户迁移，也就是说恢复所有未迁移的账户，并且在欧盟范围内，Mojang 必须是所有客户数据的所有者。
comply with contract and consumer protection laws, so notify about the changes
遵守合同和消费者保护法，因此需通知变更事项
get agreement for the changes without threatening a consequence for disagreement
在不以不同意会产生后果相威胁的情况下，取得对变更的同意
remove unenforceable clauses, including hidden clauses like the one that allows gambling
删除不可执行的条款，包括隐藏条款，例如允许赌博的条款
clearly indicate when changes happen, and comply with the terms of our old contracts.
清楚地表明何时发生变更，并遵守我们旧合同的条款。
I think these goals are re- both reasonable and achievable
我认为这些目标既合理又可实现
and saying that is coming from looking at what this case is all about
而这样说是基于对这个案件本质的了解
which is, uh, a big corporation abusing consumer rights and doing so without anybody responding to it would be wrong.
也就是说，呃，一个大公司侵犯消费者权益，而没有人对此作出回应，这是不对的。
But as you might have expected, the legal system is kind of complicated
但正如你可能预料的那样，法律体系有点复杂
because if we take these two examples, even though the core of the issue is the same
因为如果我们看这两个例子，尽管问题的核心是相同的
our contracts, there's a difference in who was affected by them.
我们的合同中，受影响的人有所不同。
Basically, you need to have the same kind of damage and the same kind of circumstances for everybody that
基本上，所有参与集体诉讼的人都需要有相同类型的损害和相同类型的情况。
uh, goes into the class action.
呃，才能加入集体诉讼。
So they would each have a different way of approaching it legally
所以他们在法律上会有不同的处理方式
some being easier to pursue than others, which is why the account migration is such a great option
有些比其他的更容易追究，这就是为什么账户迁移是一个很好的选择
because you paid for something which they then took from you under threat
因为你为某样东西付了钱，而他们却在威胁下把它从你那里夺走
all of which is very easily quantifiable damages
所有这些都是非常容易量化的损害
which basically affected everyone before 2023, including those who did migrate because it was done under threat.
这基本上在 2023 年之前影响了所有人，包括那些确实迁移了的人，因为这是在威胁下进行的。
And since the account migration is tied to our contracts
而且由于账户迁移与我们的合同绑定
just like everything else, we can then use it to resolve most issues with a single process.
就像其他所有事情一样，我们可以用一个流程来解决大多数问题。
We need to decide on how we formulate this claim.
我们需要决定如何表述这一主张。
What is the damage that's been done and how are we going to prove that?
造成了什么损害，我们将如何证明这一点？
And, uh, actually the evidence is gonna decide for us how we're gonna do this.
而且，嗯，实际上证据会为我们决定我们将如何处理这件事。
And that is the reason for this video
这就是制作本视频的原因
because we are now at the stage where we need you
因为我们现在已经到了需要你
the Minecraft player, to say that you want to participate in the class action lawsuit
这位《Minecraft》玩家，来表明你想参与集体诉讼的阶段
and to tell us how you were affected so that we can then identify and form the group that will participate.
并告诉我们你受到了怎样的影响，这样我们就能确定并组建将要参与的团队。
And the more submissions we get, the more likely we are to achieve what we've set out to do and show Mojang that they don't get to do whatever the fuck they want.
我们收到的提交越多，我们就越有可能实现我们的目标，并向 Mojang 表明他们不能为所欲为。
Obviously, it's always decided on the evidence and how well we can present that to a court and make them understand what's actually at stake here
显然，这一切总是取决于证据，以及我们能多好地将其呈现给法庭，让他们明白这里真正的利害关系。
which is the consumer's, uh, right to actually resist being abused by a big company.
这是消费者，呃，真正有权利去抵制被大公司欺压。
Where the first thing I want to say is thank you
我首先想说的是谢谢你们
because it's thanks to those donations that we now actually have a chance to fight back in a way that's never really been done before
因为正是有了这些捐助，我们现在才真正有机会以一种前所未有的方式进行反击。
and if we win, Mojang will also have to pay back our legal costs
如果我们赢了，Mojang 也必须偿还我们的法律费用
which also unfortunately goes the other way, meaning that I would essentially go bankrupt if we were to lose
但不幸的是，这种情况也可能反过来，这意味着如果我们输了，我基本上会破产
which is always a possibility.
而这种情况总是有可能发生的。
But I don't want to live with the regret of not trying simply because I was too afraid of losing.
但我不想因为害怕失败而不去尝试，从而带着遗憾生活。
So bring it on, Mojang.
那就放马过来吧，Mojang。
I'll see you in court.
法庭上见。
And even though it feels a little bit wrong to mention it
即使提到这件事感觉有点不太合适
we are fighting a billion-dollar corporation that can shit out money faster than privacy violations.
我们正在对抗一家能比侵犯隐私更快地吐出金钱的市值数十亿美元的公司。
If you do feel like supporting what we're doing
如果你确实想支持我们正在做的事情
the GoFundMe still exists.
GoFundMe 仍然存在。